Guide to the Yvor Winters and Janet Lewis papers, 1906-1982
Department of Special Collections
- SERIES II: JANET LEWIS PAPERS
  - PROFESSIONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - GENERAL
      - Doubleday, 1936-1946 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Doubleday, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Doubleday, 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Doubleday, 1960-1966 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Dumke-Freinds (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - G (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - H (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - J-L (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - M (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - N (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - O-P (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Rapp- Reader's Digest (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Robert (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Roth- Southern Review (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - St (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Swallow, 1946-1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Swallow, 1960-1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Swallow, 1973-1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Syracuse University-University of California, Berkeley (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - University of California, Los Angeles (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - University of Chicago-Voyages (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Wells College (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Wi-Z (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - ROBERTS PAPERS
      - Roberts papers (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - WINTERS ESTATE
      - B-N (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - P-Z (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - LITERARY MANUSCRIPTS
    - ARTICLES, ESSAYS, LECTURES
      - After Father Allouez (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - A Buried Treasure (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Caroline Gordon's The Glory of Hera (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - 51 Poems by Mary Webb (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Historical Novel-Fact or Fiction (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - An Introduction to Colette (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Introduction to Dinesen (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - The Knife of the Times, review (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - The Problems of the Historical Novelist (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Problems for a Librettist (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - A Tribute to Katherine Anne Porter (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Fragments of two short papers on the historical novel (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - CHILDREN'S LITERATURE
      - The Glass Bubble, Keiko's Bubble, typescript (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Keiko's Bubble, 2 sets of proofs (Folder Oversize)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox, miscellaneous notes (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, rough draft, Chapters I-VII (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, rough draft, Chapters VIII-XI (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, rough draft, Chapters XII-XIII (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, revised draft, Chapters I-III (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, revised draft, ChaptersIV-VII (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, revised draft, Chapters VIII-XI (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, revised draft, Chapters XII-XV (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, notes and corrected typescript, Chapters I-II (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, corrected typescript, Chapters III-VI (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, corrected typescript, Chapters VII-X (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Yoshiko and the Fox,, corrected typescript, Chapters XI-XV (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - LIBRETTOS
      - Birthday for Infanta, first draft to unrevised final version (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Birthday for Infanta, 2 copies (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Candace (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - John Brown (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, notes and corrections (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, notes and draft (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, corrected typescript (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, copy and carbon synopsis (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, first copy (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, revised copy (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, photocopy, corrected (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - The Last of the Mohicans, photocopy, after corrections (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - The legend of the Neengay- An Opera-Oratorio (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - The Wife of Martin Guerre, worksheets (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - The Wife of Martin Guerre, worksheets (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - The Wife of Martin Guerre, worksheets (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - The Wife of Martin Guerre, Feb. 1956version (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - The Wife of Martin Guerre, 1956revision (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - The Wife of Martin Guerre, ephemera (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, The Spellbinder, synopsis of unfinished opera (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - NOVELS
      Invasion - see box 20, folder 8
      - Against the Darkening Sky, Title pager, pp. 1-90 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, pp. 91-180 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, pp. 181-270 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, pp. 271-329 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, The Ghost of Monsieur Scarron, plans and outlines, including The Tale (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, rough draft, Chapters 1-2 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, rough draft, Chapter 3 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, rough draft, [Chapter 5?] (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 1-5 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 6-9 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 10-13 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 14-17 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 18-21 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 22-24 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapter 25 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 26-27 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, first rough version, Chapters 28-32 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, miscellaneous first draft (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, draft, Chapters 1-9 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, draft, Chapters 10-17 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, draft, Chapters 18-22 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, draft, Chapters 23-28 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, draft, Chapters 29-39 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, final draft, Chapters 1-3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, final draft, Chapters 4-9 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, final draft, Chapters 10-16 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, final draft, Chapters 17-22 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Against the Darkening Sky,, final draft, Chapters 23-end (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, first draft, pp. 1-50 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, first draft, pp. 51-100 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, first draft, pp. 101-150 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, first draft, pp. 151-204 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, [final?] draft, pp. 1-50, also 1946 foreword (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, [final?] draft, pp. 51-100 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, [final?] draft, pp. 101-150 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, [final?] draft, pp. 151-208, corrections (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - The Trial of Soren Quist, revised foreword (1966) (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Valentine Burnet, notes for an unfinished novel (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, source material (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, source material (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, draft (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, corrected typescript (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, typescript (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, revised foreword (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - the Wife of Martin Guerre, Reader's Digest Condensed version, Canadian edition (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - POEMS
      - The Earth Bound, Poems 1918-1941,typescript (later revised) (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - The Earth Bound, Poems 1924-1944,typescript (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - The Earth Bound, proofs (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Poems 1924-1944,typescripts (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Poems 1924-1944, 1 copy (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,publisher's notes and correspondence (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, first typescript, first half (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, first typescript, second half (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, typescript, photocopy (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, typescript, second photocopy (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, corrected galleys, author's copy (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, corrected galleys, frontis information (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Poems Old and New 1918-1978,, uncorrected galleys (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Untitled typescript (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Grouped typescripts (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Book of poems made for Elizabeth Taylor Lewis (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Individual poems [by title, untitled poems last] (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - RADIO BROADCASTS
      - Wife of Martin Guerre, BBC radio-play script (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - SHORT STORIES
      - List of titles with publishing information (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Apricot Harvest (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Bokhara (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - The Breakable Cup, 2 copies (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Furlough, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - The Gift (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Goodbye, Son (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - The House (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - The Invention of the Flute, 3 copies (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - :The Journey of the Purple Pantaoufles of Grandmere (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Life and Death of a Giant (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Little Hell Cat (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - A Long Ride to Arizona (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Madame Chrysantheme (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Nell (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - People Don't Want Us, working title: Fish Kites for Big Day (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Picnic 1943,or Seeing is Disbelieving, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Proserpina (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Quarentine for Miranda (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - River (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - A Room for my Son, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Soldier's Return (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - The Still Afternoon, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Summer Parties (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Sunday Dinner (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - A Twice Told Tale, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - MISCELLANEOUS
      - Fragments, notes (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Notebook (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - MISCELLANEOUS SUBJECT FILES
    - Book catalogues (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Music (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Poetry readings, invitations (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Teaching materials (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - University of California, Berkeley, English 108, Women Writers (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - NEWSCLIPPINGS
    - About Janet Lewis (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Reviews of Janet Lewis' work (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Reviews of Janet Lewis' work (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Reviews of Janet Lewis' work (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Reviews of Janet Lewis' work (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of Janet Lewis' work (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Abe-Ghose (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Holt-Roberts (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Salvi-Christiani - Wheeler (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Wife- Winters (Box 20, Folder 7)
- SERIES III: RELATED MATERIALS
  - GYROSCOPE
    - May, 1929issue (photocopy [UNK] Harnie Furbush, May 1979 (Box 20, Folder 9a)
    - Notebook - Invasion background (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - August 1929issue (Box 20, Folder 9b)
    - November 1929issue (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - February 1930issue (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - SCORES
    - Birthday for Infanta (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Janet's Lullaby and Lullaby (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - ARTICLES, ESSAYS BY FAMILY, FRIENDS, AND FORMER STUDENTS
    - Baker-Cassity (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Davie-Fields (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Fraser-Glenn (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Graff-v. Hallberg (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Inglis-Kaye (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Nixon-Parkinson (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Powell (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - SAMLA-Stanford (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Van Deusen-Zelditch (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - INTERVIEWS WITH JANET LEWIS
    - Carnochan (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Hamovitch (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - POEMS BY FREINDS AND FORMER STUDENTS
    - A-C (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - D-F (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - G-Ramsey (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Roberts (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Rubin-S (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - T (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - W (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - OTHER
    - California Writer's Conference, poems (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Overton, David, the Dark Shadow (from a novel by Janet Lewis) (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous newsclippings (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Talk by Ken Fields (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Talk by Henry Ramsey and Edgar Bower (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Photographs for Special Collections exhibit (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Photographs for Special Collections exhibit (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Photographs for Special Collections exhibit, mounted (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Photographs for Special Collections exhibit, mounted (Box 22, Folder 13)
Separated Materials
Materials transferred to Felton Collection
1. (3 vols. of) The Gyroscope, ed. by Yvor Winters, Janet Lewis, and Howard Baker. Nov. 1929, Feb. 1930 (2 copies).
2. Winters, Yvor. The Bare Hills. Four Seas: Boston, 1927.
3. Winters, Yvor. The Brink of Darkness. The Swallow Pamphlets Number 15: Denver, n.d.
4. Winters, Yvor. The Immobile Wind. Monroe Wheeler: Evanston, Ill., 1921.
5. Winters, Yvor. In Defense of Reason. 3rd. ed. Alan Swallow: Denver, 1947.(Kenneth Fields copy of the book with his margin notes, underlining, etc...)
Materials transferred to Archives (from Lewis/Winters)
Stanford Teaching Materials
Folder 1. Yvor Winters. Reading Lists:
English 18, 5pp.
English 190, Chief American Poets, 7pp.
English 251, The English Lyric, 6pp.
English 266, Chief American Poets, 12pp.
English 266, Chief American Poets, Winter 1966, 12pp.
Folder 2. Yvor Winters. Teaching Materials: Poems, 21pp.
Folder 3. Janet Lewis. Teaching Materials:
Narration 5, syllabus. 3pp. typewritten draft, 2pp. mimeo.
Narration 5, Winter 1970, syllabus. 1p. typewritten draft, 1p. mimeo.
Course outlines/syllabi in JL's hand, 2pp.
Notes on students, papers, student grades, 46 leaves
Notebook. Notes on students, papers.
Folder 4. Freshman English Program for 1966-7, booklet.